vegasslotsonline.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy page

## Our Privacy and Data Policy

Unless you live in a cave, you’ll have received a lot of e-mails recently. They will all have told you that you need to do something by May 25th. Chances are that it’s been along the lines of “Click this box if you want to go on receiving our e-mails.” (And even if you do live in a cave, someone’s probably tapped on your rock and said, “You need to chisel your name on this tablet of stone…”)

### Why?

The reason is GDPR – the General Data Protection Regulation. It’s a new piece of legislation from the European Union that affects companies or organisations that hold data about EU citizens – whether they are inside or outside the EU.

We’re no exception – and so we’ve set out below our privacy and data policy: why we collect your data, what we collect, how we keep it and what we’ll do if you don’t want us to hold that data any more.

The GDPR regulations are complicated. We’ve done our best to simplify them, and make them as readable as possible. But if you still have questions when you’ve finished reading them, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with us.

### So what’s GDPR?

It’s a regulation in EU law dealing with data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union and the European Economic Area. It also covers exporting that data outside the EU – so if, for example, you’re an American company and you deal with EU citizens’ data, you have to comply with GDPR. Its primary aim is to give individuals much more control over their personal data, and it came into effect on Friday May 25th 2018.

The regulation requires ‘processors of data’ – essentially, companies and organisations – to disclose what data is being collected, why it’s being collected, how and why it is processed, how long it is retained for and whether it is shared with any third parties.

Let’s dive into the detail…

### The Data Protection Officer

The DPO is going to be an important person in most companies and organisations. Any public authority or business who regularly process personal data must have a Data Protection Officer who is responsible for ensuring compliance with the GDPR regulations, and reporting any data breaches within 72 hours if they impact on user privacy.

### Who are we?

First things first: who are we? We’re essentially a review and information site. Our aim is to give you all the information you need to make the best possible choice when you’re deciding on an online casino to sign up with. We do that by regularly researching all the casinos and games providers out there, writing what we hope are helpful reviews and negotiating special offers, bonuses and “freebies” on your behalf. In short, we’ll help you choose an online casino, and help you obtain the best possible offers from that casino.

### Supposing I want to contact you?

No problem at all: we’d be happy to hear from you.

If you have a general question about the site, then contact us at info@vegasslotsonline.com

If you have an online casino that you’d like us to feature, then contact our commercial team on commercial@vegasslotsonline.com

Finally – and most importantly – if you have a question about your personal data then you should contact our Data Protection Officer, whose email address is: dpo@vegasslotsonline.com

### The data we hold about you

We couldn’t operate effectively or efficiently if we didn’t hold some personal data – but we give you the option to decide what data we hold. We do this by splitting our data into two distinct categories: Population Metrics and Personal Information.

### Population Metrics

This is data which is completely anonymised – and cannot be “reversed” in any way to reveal your identity. Let me explain how it works.

Assume you visit our site for the first time. When you do that, we automatically assign a random number to you, which is stored in a cookie (a small piece of information) on your browser. You get a cookie for each page you visit. Next time you visit our site – assuming you haven’t deleted your cookies – the process starts again.

Why do we do this? Because tracking what pages people visit and how they move from page to page is important to us. But it is the anonymous, aggregated data that is important. We do not track individual visits – but if you want to opt out of our population metrics, you can do that by following the information here:

### Personal Data

We only collect personal data in one case – when you actively opt-in to our newsletter. Then we collect your e-mail address, and that’s all we collect. As you probably know, we will send you a verification e-mail. Once you reply to this, we start the process of sending you regular e-mails. However, if someone does not reply to the verification e-mail within two weeks, then we delete your e-mail from our list.

If you feel that you would like to opt-out of the e-mails you receive from us then you can do this in one of two ways:

Click on the unsubscribe button that is on every e-mail we send you

Or, e-mail our DPO and ask to be unsubscribed. The address is dpo@vegasslotsonline.com

In both cases, we will remove you from our e-mail list, and remove any data that we hold about you.

If you are unsure as to whether you are on our e-mail list, then you can find out by e-mailing our DPO on the address above.

### Active Campaign

Like the vast majority of companies and organisations, we use an external company to send our e-mails and monitor such exciting data as open rates and clicks on any links in the e-mail. The company we use is called Active Campaign and if you need to know any more about them, this link takes you to their website: https://www.activecampaign.com/

### How does it work?

Once you sign up to our e-mails, your e-mail address is securely stored with Active Campaign. When one of our marketing managers has written an e-mail, they use the relevant information on Active Campaign to send it out. Active Campaign monitors the response stats for us and, as above, every e-mail will give you the option to unsubscribe should you no longer wish to hear from us.

### A table!

At this point we have summarised “the story so far.”

The table lists all the data we collect, the processing we do, who can access the data, how long they hold it for and who collects the data. Remember, if you have any questions on this – or any aspect of our data collection – then please do not hesitate to contact our DPO.

Script Info  
---  
**Google Analytics  
Google Inc. **  
Privacy Matters   
Twitter Inc.   
1600 Amphitheatre Parkway,   
Mountain View, CA, 94043   
USA  

Google Analytics is a set of tools that collects and uses information for statistical research and for online advertising tracking and optimization purposes. 

_Our Usage_  
We use Google Analytics to be able to optimize our website designs, gain insight on popular features, identify usage trends, track the delivery of our promotional content and, more generally, to know our market better in terms of geographical distribution, demography and usage patterns.   
  
Legal Basis  
Our legal basis for using this script within our website is a legitimate business interest. Without using Google Analytics, we would not be able to constantly update the website to ensure that we are providing you with the best services that we can provide you with relative to the competition. All the data that is provided to us by this script is either anonymous or pseudonymous and therefore serves a function strictly in relation to research that we conduct to be able to continuously improve our services. 

_You may still opt-out of type of tracking by using the DNT feature on your browser or by installing;  
[Google Analytics Opt-out browser plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) _  
  
Data Collected & Retention  
_Anonymous_  
Ad Views, Analytics, Browser Information, Cookie Data, Date/Time, Demographic Data, Hardware/Software Type, Internet Service Provider, Page Views, Serving Domains 

_Pseudonymous_  
Search History, Location Based Data 

_Personally Identifiable Information_  
IP Address, Unique Device ID 

_Data Sharing_  
Aggregate data, Anonymous data and PII data might be shared by Google with third parties, but not with us. Personally Identifiable Information may also be shared with third parties. 

_Data Retention_  
Your data is stored indefinitely   
  
Script Info  
**Twitter Button & Twitter Syndication  
Twitter Inc. **  
Twitter, Inc.   
1355 Market Street,   
Suite 900,   
San Francisco CA 94103   
California   
USA   
privacy@twitter.com 

Twitter Button and Twitter Syndication are two social media trackers belonging to Twitter. When You use the Twitter button (including tweet and share) or widget, Twitter will receive information about You and a Twitter cookie will be stored on Your device. 

_Our Usage_  
Twitter uses the information that it receives from its button and syndication trackers to customize the marketing content that Twitter shows You, including targeted ads. Twitter also uses the data for the purposes described in its privacy policy, for which a link is provided below, which include selling aggregate data to third-parties.   
  
Legal Basis  
Our legal basis for using these scripts within Our website is Our legitimate interest. Part of our marketing strategy entails using Pay-Per-Click marketing and the billable cost for this cannot be estimated to any reasonable degree of accuracy without any form of tracking. We do not receive any Personally Identifiable Data through this script, although Twitter might be able to identify You personally. 

<https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en> The data that Twitter may receive includes: IP address, browser type, operating system, hardware type, internet service provider, search history, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device information (including device and application IDs), search terms, or cookie information. Twitter also receives log data when You click on, view or interact with links on Twitter’s website or through its services, including links to third-party applications.   
  
Data Collected & Retention  
_Anonymous_  
Analytics, Browser Information, Cookie Data, Date/Time, Demographic Data, Hardware/Software Type, Internet Service Provider, Interaction Data, Page Views 

_Pseudonymous_  
Search History, Location Based Data 

_Personally Identifiable Information_  
IP Address, Device ID, Name, Address, Phone Number, Email Address, Login, Financial Information 

_Data Sharing_  
Aggregate, Anonymous and Personally Identifiable data is shared with third parties. Special categories of data are also shared with third parties. 

_Data Retention_  
Your data retention period is based on your profile setting with Twitter.  
Please contact Twitter for more information.   
  
Script Info  
**Facebook Impressions  
Facebook Inc. **  
1601 Willow Road,   
Menlo Park,   
California CA 94025   
USA   

Facebook Impressions is a piece of code that counts the total number of views, previews and actions that a Facebook page receives in a given period and also tracks traffic sent to Our website from Facebook. This information is provided to us in a totally anonymous way and is made accessible to us through the Facebook Insights dashboard. 

_Our Usage_  
Facebook Impressions is used to enable Us to research the efficiency and effectiveness of Our marketing through the Facebook platform. This enables Us to gain an insight on Our web marketing in relation to the Actions undertaken on Our Facebook Page including how many times our ads were viewed, and what actions they have resulted in.   
  
Legal Basis  
Our legal basis for using this script within Our website is Our legitimate interest. Part of our marketing strategy entails using Pay-Per-Click marketing and the billable cost for this cannot be estimated to any reasonable degree of accuracy without any form of tracking. We do not receive any Personally Identifiable Data through this script, although Facebook might be able to identify You personally. 

Data Collected & Retention  
_Anonymous_  
Browser Information, Date/Time, Demographic Data, Hardware/Software Type, Internet Service Provider, Interaction Data, Page Views 

_Pseudonymous_  
Location Based Data 

_Personally Identifiable Information_  
IP Address, Name, Address, Phone Number, Email Address, Login 

_Data Sharing_  
Aggregate, Anonymous and Personally Identifiable data is shared with third parties. Special categories of data are also shared with third parties. 

_Data Retention_  
Your data is stored for 6 months   
  
### Your rights: our obligations

GDPR gives you certain rights and imposes certain obligations on us, and all companies and organisations that handle your data. At any point while we are in possession of your data you can take the following action:

You can exercise your “right to be forgotten”

Yes, I know it sounds like Blofeld on a bad day. “I will exercise your right to be forgotten, Mr Bond…”

What it means though is exactly that. You can ask us to delete all the data we hold on you. We will do that, and pass on your request to any relevant third-party vendors, within 28 days of your request.

You can ask that we stop processing your data

In this case we will stop using your data and anonymize all the data we hold on you. Again, we will pass your request on to any third-party vendors within 28 days of you making the request.

You can request access to your data

In this case we will send you an e-mail file with all the data we have collected about you. Please note that we may need to verify your identity and/or contact details before we send this out: in such a case our DPO would contact you to obtain any necessary information.

You can ask us to correct your data

If you think some of the data we hold about you is wrong, or incorrect, you can ask that we correct that data. As above, we will also pass on the request to relevant third-party vendors.

You can impose restrictions on the processing of your data

It is fair to say that we already restrict our data processing to the bare minimum. As we’ve explained above, it is the aggregate of data that is important to us, not individual data. However, GDPR puts you in control of how your data is used and should you wish to impose any further restrictions on how we use your data then we will comply with that request.

You can object to profiling and/or direct marketing

Sometimes we deliver special offers or marketing initiatives on our site. We do this because we believe the offers will be of benefit to our site users – however, should you prefer not to see them then we will respect your wishes and take the necessary action.

Finally, you can ask that we move your data to a third-party location

…And like all the points above, we’ll be happy to comply with your request.

### Complaints

If, for any reason, you want to complain about the way in which we have handled your data then please contact our DPO with your complaint.

Similarly you should also contact our DPO to access any of the rights we have listed above – or if you simply want to confirm that we are doing our very best to protect your data, and that we are using it in the correct way.

### That’s it…

Thank you for reading this far. We appreciate that GDPR is a complicated subject, but we have done our best to make it as simple as possible. Rest assured that we have always taken our obligations regarding your data very seriously, and we will continue to do in the future. We’ll work as hard on that as we do on bringing you the best casino reviews, offers and incentives.

The vegasslotsonline.com team
